Andreas Ziegler

Robotics & Computer Vision Researcher/Engineer

Zihlweg 22 8712 Stäfa Switzerland \Box +41 (0)79 581 46 90 **☑** 062.127@gmail.com 3 andreasaziegler.github.io in andreas-ziegler



Summary

I am passionate about a mix of robotics and computer vision research and industrial/commercial applications. My vision is to develop novel algorithms and make them work on real robots. I enjoy working independently on research and engineer projects, but I also appreciate the opportunity to exchange ideas with a variety of individuals from various backgrounds.

Personal details

Date of birth 25.03.1988

Nationality Swiss

Education

05.2021- PhD Candidate, University of Tübingen, Tübingen, Germany

Thesis: Event-based computer vision for fast robot control

- In collaboration with Sony AI Zürich
- O Thesis supervisors: Prof. Dr. Andreas Zell and Prof. Dr. Andreas Geiger

09.2014–04.2018 MSc ETH in EEIT, ETH Zürich, Zürich, Switzerland

Specialized in: Robotics, Computer Vision and Machine Learning

Master Thesis: A Representation for Exploration that is Robustto State Estimate Drift

- O Examiner: Prof. Dr. Roland Siegwart and Prof. Dr. Davide Scaramuzza
- Resulted in [4]

Semester Project 2: Map Fusion for Collaborative UAV SLAM

- O Examiner: Prof. Dr. Roland Siegwart and Prof. Dr. Margarita Chli
- Semester Project 1: Robust object tracking in 3D by fusing ultra-wideband and vision
- O Examiner: Prof. Dr. Luc Van Gool and Prof. Dr. Otmar Hilliges

09.2009–09.2013 BSc FHO in Electrical Engineering, University of Applied Science Eastern Switzerland (HSR), Rapperswil, Switzerland

> Specialized in: Digital Signal and Image Processing, Embedded Systems and Software Engineering, and Mobile Communication

09.2011-08.2012 Exchange year, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai, China

Courses taken: Chinese language, Electrical engineering and Computer Science

Independent Coursework

edX DT-01x: Self-Driving Cars with Duckietown by ETHx on edX. Specialization Certificate earned on August 15, 2021

Coursera Deep Learning, a 5-course specialization by deeplearning ai on Coursera. Specialization Certificate earned on March 16, 2018

Autonomous Mobile Robots by ETHx on edX. Certificate earned on April 17, 2014

Work experience

06.2021-present PhD Candidate, University of Tübingen, Tübingen, Germany, 100%

- O Working on event-based computer vision for fast robot control in collaboration with Sony AI Zürich
- Supervision of MSc and BSc students
- Teaching Assistant

Technologies used: C++, Python, Julia, PyTorch, OpenCV, numpy, Eigen, ROS1/2, git, IAT_FX

08.2022–10.2022 Computer Vision & ML Research Intern, Prophesee, Paris, France, 100% Worked on slow motion from frame and event data under the supervison of Dr. Amos Sironi

Technologies used: Python, PyTorch, OpenCV, numpy, git, Atlassian tools

09.2018–05.2021 Robotics Engineer, MT-Robot AG, Zwingen, Switzerland, 100%

Accomplished tasks:

- Development of a computer vision based safety field intrusion detection system
- Improvement of a multi robot collision avoidance system
- O Development and maintenance of software for autonomous mobile robots (AMRs), including topics such as multi sensor fusion, mapping, path planning, (multi robot) obstacle avoidance, etc.
- O Deputy Scrum Master

Technologies used: C++, Python, ROS1/2, DDS, OpenCV, CMake, git, Atlassian tools

06.2018-09.2018 Research Assistant, University of Zürich, Robotics and Perception Group, Zurich, Switzerland, 100%

Continued working on my master thesis project which lead to [4]

04.2018–06.2018 Research Associate Intern, Disney Research Zürich, Zürich, Switzerland, 100% Integrated a Leica total station in an existing ROS setup within the PaintCopter project. Technologies used: C++, Python, ROS, Ceres, CMake, git

02.2018–03.2018 Research Assistant, Laboratory for Orthopaedic Biomechanics at the University and ETH Zürich, Zürich, Switzerland, 100%

> Developed an LED light controller for a microscope setup which contributed to [3]. Technologies used: C++, Qt, wxWidgets, CMake, git

03.2017-08.2017 Computer Vision & Robotics Research Intern, Pix4D SA, Lausanne, Switzerland, 100%

Accomplished tasks:

- Worked on indoor navigation for UAVs
- Implementation of a filtering method for a robust target detection
- Participation on an indoor mapping project with an industrial partner
- Investigation of barcode localization and detection algorithms for automatic inventory
- Participation on a development of a target detection library for radiometric corrections
- Worked on various computer vision applications (Barcode localization/detection, 3D reconstruction, Camera calibration)

Technologies used: C++, ROS, OpenCV, Eigen, Conan, CMake, Jenkins, git

08.2015–06.2018 Software Engineer & System Administrator, Accelerom AG, Zürich, Switzerland, 20%-30%

> Technologies used: Java, Groovy, JavaScript, jQuery, CSS, Grails, Hibernate, MySQL, git, Redmine, Tomcat, Apache, SAMBA

02.2014–08.2015 Research Assistant, Laboratory for Orthopaedic Biomechanics at the University and ETH Zürich, Zürich, Switzerland, 100%/20%

Continued my work, provided further consulting and maintenance.

11.2013–02.2014 Research Assistant (Civil service), Computer Assisted Research and Development, University Hospital Balgrist, Zürich, Switzerland, 100%

Worked on segmentation algorithms for computer assisted surgical planning

Worked on segmentation algorithms for computer-assisted surgical planning Technologies used: Matlab, C#, VTK, CVS

08.2013–11.2013 Research Assistant (Civil service), Laboratory for Orthopaedic Biomechanics at the University and ETH Zürich, Zürich, Switzerland, 100%

Accomplished tasks:

- O Extended and adapted a microscope control software which contributed to [2]
- O Developed and implemented a stretcher control software

Technologies used: C++, Qt, wxWidgets, CMake, git

08.2008–03.2009 Computer Science Intern, ERPsourcing AG, Wallisellen, Switzerland, 100%

08.2004–08.2008 Electronics Engineer Apprentice, Hch. Kündig & Cie. AG, Rüti ZH, Switzerland, 100%

Publications

- [1] A. Ziegler, D. Teigland, J. Tebbe, T. Gossard, and A. Zell, *Real-time event simulation with frame-based cameras*, 2022. DOI: 10.48550/ARXIV.2209.04634. [Online]. Available: https://arxiv.org/abs/2209.04634.
- [2] A. Horvath, A. Ziegler, S. Gerhard, et al., "Focus on time: Dynamic imaging reveals stretch-dependent cell relaxation and nuclear deformation," Biophysical Journal, Jan. 2021. DOI: 10.1016/j.bpj.2021.01.020.
- [3] A. N. Horvath, A. A. Ziegler, S. Gerhard, et al., "Time-controlled multichannel dynamic traction imaging of biaxially stretched adherent cells," Mar. 2020. DOI: 10.1101/2020.03.02.972919. [Online]. Available: https://doi.org/10.1101/2020.03.02.972919.
- [4] T. Cieslewski, A. Ziegler, and D. Scaramuzza, "Exploration without global consistency using local volume consolidation," in *IFRR International Symposium on Robotics Research (ISRR)*, Hanoi, 2019, IFRR: IEEE, Oct. 2019. [Online]. Available: https://doi.org/10.5167/uzh-197724.

Languages

German Mother tongue

English Excellent, Level C1

French Good, Level B1,

Korean Basics, Level A2

Chinese Basics, Level A1

Technical skills

Languages C++, Python, Julia, C, Java

Software packages OpenCV, ROS1/2, PyTorch, Eigen, boost, DDS, pcl, scikit-learn, wxWidgets, Qt, MATLAB

Hobbies

Sports Wing Chun Kung Fu, Yoga, Jogging, Mountaineering

Music Drums, Piano, Vocals

Extra-Curricular activities

o Foodsaver at Foodsharing, managing a Labdoo hub